Marge Champion Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Musical Theater and Plays, Films and Television (Box 1-7, 22-27)
  - Television (Box 4, 6)
    - Publicity tours: photographs (including 1959 Ed Sullivan Russia tour) (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Publicity with celebrities: photographs and clippings (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Queen of the Stardust Ballroom: clippings, photographs, correspondence, Emmy program and nomination, shooting schedule and script (Box-folder 4/9 and 6/6)
    - Reingold beer photographs, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Television clippings, correspondence and photographs (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Television photographs, clippings, TV concepts from “2 x 2 x 2” and “From Hollywood to Broadway” (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Orchestrations (Box 22-26)
    - Music scores by Jay Gorney, 1941-1944, 1964, 1969, Printed and photocopied scores; Songs from Meet the People: Union Label Twenty-five Bucks a Week Opening to Meet the People Meet the People In-Chi-Chi-Castenango A Fellow and a Girl The Four Rivers Honey Trust Me That Mittel-Europa of Mine Let’s Steal a Tune (2 copies) The Stars Remain Unser Amerika It’s the Same Old South Loyal Americans Mrs. Yiffnif The Bill of Rights It’s No Fun Eating Alone (Box-folder 22/5)
    - At Home, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 26/7)
    - Bows, Manuscript parts (Box-folder 25/7)
    - Buddy’s Butler-Aida, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 25/6)
    - Comm. Tag 1 and 2, Manuscript parts (Box-folder 25/10)
    - County Fair, registered in 1949, Manuscript score and parts; One arrangement by Phil J. Lavy. (Box-folder 22/1-2)
    - Dancing Tag, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 24/1)
    - Eye to Eye, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 26/6)
    - $15,000, Cue, manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 25/11)
    - Hang Up, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 25/3)
    - Hotel Room, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 26/4)
    - Jeune Fillette, registered in 1947, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 23/3)
    - Let’s Dance, Manuscript score and parts; Manuscript parts registered in 1959. (Box-folder 24/4)
    - Let’s Dance, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 24/3)
    - Let’s Dance, Manuscript scores and parts; Arranged by Pete Rugolo, music by Richard Prigor, parts were registered in 1959. (Box-folder 24/5)
    - Let’s Dance, Manuscript theme score and parts (Box-folder 26/2)
    - M-100 Stage Ten, Manuscript score and parts; For the Marge and Gower Champion Show. (Box-folder 25/9)
    - M-102 Which Dance, Manuscript score and parts; For the Marge and Gower Champion Show. (Box-folder 25/5)
    - No Phone, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 25/4)
    - “Opening” March 31, Manuscript score and parts; For the Marge and Gower Champion Show. (Box-folder 26/3)
    - “Opening” for Marge and Gower Champion, Manuscript score and parts; For the Marge and Gower Champion Show. (Box-folder 25/1)
    - Opening, Manuscript score and parts; Names written on the manuscript are Jack Latimer and Jeff Bailey. (Box-folder 24/2)
    - Orchestrations inventory (Box-folder 26/1)
    - Re-encounter, registered 1949, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 23/1)
    - They’re Off, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 26/5)
    - Time on my Hands, registered 1959, Manuscript parts; Arranged by Harry Zimmerman and Al Woodbury. (Box-folder 23/4)
    - Time on my Hands, Manuscript score (Box-folder 22/3)
    - Vaudeville, registered 1941, Manuscript score and parts (Box-folder 23/2)
    - Wild flower, Manuscript score and parts; Arranged by Grau. (Box-folder 25/2)
    - Wrong Door, Manuscript score and parts; For the Marge and Gower Champion Show. (Box-folder 25/8)
- Photographs (Box 5, 7-8, 19, 21, 26, 33)
  - American Women for International Understanding (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Beach photographs (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Ernest Belcher's pupils and dancers at the Hollywood Bowl, Removed for conservation, 6/12/2012. (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Ernest Belcher's students at the Hollywood Bowl, Removed for conservation, 6/12/2012. (Box-folder 33/5)
  - Historical photographs related to Ernest Belcher (Box-folder 8/2-3, 21/5, 26/8)
  - Photographs from the book Before the parade passes by: Gower Champion and the glorious American musical by John Anthony Gilvey, Photocopies (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Gower Champion photographs (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Gower Champion photographs (glamour shots, youth) (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Gower Champion rehearsal photographs from Hello Dolly!, Photographs taken by Helen Montgomery. (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Marge Champion at movie sets (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Modeling and fashion shots of Marge Champion (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Marge Champion photographs (Box-folder 8/6-7)
  - Photographs related to Marge Champion (Box-folder 26/9)
  - De Mille, Agnes (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Materials relating to Disney animator Bill Tytla, including clippings, photocopies of letters, drawings, photographs, maps, articles and booklet on Tytla (Box-folder 5/11)
- Personal and Business Papers (Box 9-12)
  Clippings, correspondence, photographs, programs, publicity materials, biographical materials, contracts and other materials
  - Basquette, Lina, Clippings, correspondence and photographs; Includes old photographs of Lina, her daughter, and Lina as a newlywed with the Warner family. (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Belcher, Ernest: various materials, Includes materials on the Nartell Twins, Alexander the Man Who Knows (correspondence, clippings, photographs), photographs of Bowl Symphony, article on Belcher, book from the Ernest Belcher Celeste School of Dancing (1924), program, and publicity materials. (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Blake’s Barn, Jacob’s Pillow, Clippings, correspondence, invitation, program, architectural materials and plans, and photographs (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Candid shots, Clippings and photographs (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Champion, Blake, Clippings, program, correspondence and photographs (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Champion, Gower, War ration books, passport, notes, clippings, correspondence, speech notes, copy of playbill with Gower and Jeanne (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Champion, Gregg, Resumé, clippings, program and photographs (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Champion, Marge, biographical information, Photographs, biographical notes, thesis, correspondence, clippings, birth certificate and notes (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Champion, Marge, childhood, Certificate, programs, photographs, notes, correspondence, papers written by Marge, autograph book (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Champion, Marge and Gower, wedding and anniversaries, Invitation, certificate, photographs and correspondence (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Church and liturgical dance records, Notes, scores, correspondence, programs, photographs and printed material (8 folders) (Box-folder 11/4-7, 12/1-4)
  - Contracts, correspondence and agreements (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Family photographs (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Sagal, Boris, Clippings, photographs and correspondence (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Sagal, Boris: The Awakening Land, Photographs, correspondence, clippings and notes (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Sagal, Boris: Masada, Clippings, photographs and award certificate (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Sagal, Boris, Production photographs, clippings, program and correspondence (Box-folder 10/6)
- Subject Files (Box 13-19)
  Clippings, photographs, correspondence, programs, notes, promotional materials, articles and other materials.
  - Academy Awards, 1958, Clippings and photographs (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Academy Awards, 1986, Clippings, program, detailed schedule and photographs (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Acting class: Marge’s notebooks and notes (Box-folder 13/2)
  - American Arts Alliance, Clippings, correspondence, schedule, program and score (Box-folder 13/5)
  - American Choreographic Award, Clippings and program (Box-folder 13/6)
  - American Film Institute Riverwalk, Correspondence, clippings and photographs (Box-folder 15/6)
  - American Women for International Understanding, Magazines, programs, maps, drawing, correspondence and schedule (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Babbitt, Art, Clippings (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Balanchine oral history: interview with Marge Champion and Patricia Marshall, Notes, correspondence, programs and clippings; Includes George Antheil's original letter to Balanchine from 1945. (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Ballroom Theater Award, Speech notes, clippings, correspondence, program and photographs (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Bolden, Mel, Clippings, correspondence and booklet (Box-folder 18/5)
  - Boston Conservatory of Music, Correspondence, speech notes, clippings and photographs; Includes Marge Champion's honorary doctor of fine arts award. (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Brockway, Merrill, Clippings, speech notes, program and article (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Carnegie Hall, Clippings, stage bill, correspondence, schedule and speech notes (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Cartoon Art Museum: materials on Snow White exhibit (Box-folder 18/7)
  - Center Theatre Group of Los Angeles, Clippings, correspondence, notes and programs (Box-folder 13/10)
  - Channing, Carol, Correspondence and clippings; Includes a Helen Montgomery-Drysdale photograph of Carol Channing as Dolly, 1995. (Box-folder 18/9)
  - China, Programs, notes, contacts, brochures, maps and a woodcut (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Columbia Records: Let’s Dance and Champion Strut photographs (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Commonwealth Award (Massachusetts Cultural Council), Clippings, correspondence, press releases, program, award recipients information and photographs (Box-folder 13/11)
  - Coward, Noel, Correspondence (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Crosby, Bing, Programs and photographs (Box-folder 18/10)
  - Dance Library of Israel, Speech notes, clippings, invitations, correspondence (Martha Graham and Marcel Marceau photocopies) and photographs (Box-folder 13/12)
  - Dancing Ladies, Correspondence, program information and clippings (Box-folder 13/13)
  - Davidson, Gordon, Correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 18/11)
  - De Mille, Agnes, Correspondence, clippings and production schedule (Box-folder 18/12)
  - Easter Bonnet Competition, Correspondence and program (Box-folder 13/14)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight, Correspondence (Box-folder 19/7)
  - England, 1985, Correspondence (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Fabray, Nanette, Correspondence, clippings and photographs (Box-folder 18/13)
  - Field, Ron, Clippings and correspondence (Box-folder 18/14)
  - Film Forum, Newsletters, and articles copied for Marge Champion (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Florida State Ballroom Championship, Programs (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Gilvey, John, Correspondence, clippings, interview list, reviews, notes, parts of the book and photographs (Box-folder 18/6, 18/15)
  - Graham, Martha, Correspondence and photograph (Box-folder 18/16)
  - Greece, Journal and correspondence (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Hollywood High, class of 1936, Correspondence, clippings, program, photographs and information on induction into alumni museum (Box-folder 13/15)
  - Iceland, Notes, report, brochures and correspondence (Box-folder 17/7)
  - India, Schedule, article on dance, correspondence, brochure, map and postcards (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Institute of the American Musical, Chronology, article, magazine and program (Box-folder 18/2)
  - International Ballet Competition, Invitations, correspondence, clippings, program, brochures, schedules and photographs (Box-folder 14/1-2)
  - Jacob’s Pillow, Clippings, correspondence, newsletter, program and photographs (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Jacob’s Pillow gala, 1986, Programs, clippings, news release and speech notes (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Le Divine Italy, Four booklets (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Lemmon, Jack, Program, clippings and photographs (Box-folder 18/17)
  - The Lensic (Santa Fe's Performing Arts Center), Speech notes, programs, brochures and clippings (Box-folder 14/6)
  - Let’s Dance with Marge and Gower Champion by Bob Thomas (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Lincoln Center Honors, Program, clippings, notes and correspondence (Box-folder 14/7)
  - London, 1990, Clippings, correspondence and programs (Box-folder 17/5)
  - London Palladium, Program and photographs (Box-folder 14/8)
  - Los Angeles Times, Women of the Year, Correspondence, programs and clippings (Box-folder 14/5)
  - Mafundi, 1969, Institutional information, Dr. Al Cannon correspondence, clippings, schedules, other correspondence and financial information (Box-folder 14/9)
  - Mafundi, 1970, Programs, correspondence, institution profile, clippings and public relations material (Box-folder 14/11)
  - Mafundi, 1971, Clippings, correspondence, woodcut, meeting notes and reports (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Mafundi, 1972, Schedule, reports, correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 15/2)
  - Mafundi crisis, 1973, Correspondence, meeting notes, news releases and clippings (Box-folder 15/3)
  - Mafundi, “The Blacks” production, Poster with notes, invitations, clippings, article, correspondence, notes and cast information (Box-folder 14/10)
  - Martin, Mary, Correspondence, clippings and photographs (Box-folder 18/18)
  - Miscellaneous appearances, Clippings, correspondence, programs, schedule and photographs (Box-folder 15/13, 16/3-4)
  - Miscellaneous drawings and cards, Snow White drawings and holiday card (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Miscellany, Clippings, correspondence, speech and memoir notes, program and photographs (Box-folder 16/6)
  - Names Project, Correspondence, clippings, program and photographs (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Negotiation seminar for women in film materials (Box-folder 19/3)
  - North Adams State College, Program, correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Palm Springs desert, Clippings, program, correspondence and speech notes (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Paper dolls (Box-folder 18/24)
  - Reagan, Nancy, Correspondence and photograph (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Rich, Frank, Correspondence, clippings and article (Box-folder 18/19)
  - Royal Viking, Correspondence, newsletter, schedule, notes, passenger list, clippings and photographs (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Russian trip, 1982, Notebooks and journals, programs, clippings and correspondence (Box-folder 16/8)
  - St. Denis, Ruth, “The Divine Dance”, printout (Box-folder 18/20)
  - San Francisco Ballet, “NRA” with Robert Gladstein, Correspondence, clippings, programs, magazines and photographs (Box-folder 15/7)
  - San Jose State, Clippings, press release and photographs (Box-folder 15/8)
  - Showalter, Max, Correspondence, clippings and program (Box-folder 18/21)
  - Snow College (Ephraim, Utah), Clippings and schedule (Box-folder 15/9)
  - Stapleton, Maureen, Clippings and correspondence (Box-folder 18/22)
  - State dinner with Queen Elizabeth and Prince Philip, Clippings, letter from Prince Philip, invitation, guest list and John Foster Dulles correspondence (Box-folder 15/10)
  - Symphony in three movements, Clippings and photographs (Box-folder 15/11)
  - Truman, Harry, Correspondence (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Telegrams (Box-folder 18/1)
  - UCLA film inventory, Correspondence and clippings (donation of film) (Box-folder 18/23)
  - White House Conference on Children, 1970, Clippings, bag, speech notes, programs, information booklet and notes (Box-folder 15/12)
- Clippings and Written Materials (Box 19-21, 27)
  - Champion, Marge and Gower, Journals and covers (Box-folder 20/1-2)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Clippings for Library of Congress (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Gilvey, John. Thesis: Gower Champion as Director, volume 1 of 2 (Box-folder 20/4)
  - God is a Verb (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Miscellaneous articles and clippings, Clippings, program, newsletters and photographs (Box-folder 21/2)
  - Press, Clippings and correspondence (Box-folder 19/8)
  - Publicity clippings (Box-folder 21/3)
  - Related journals, including Marcel Marceau signed cover (Box-folder 19/9)
  - Related published material (Box-folder 27/3)
  - Related theater journals (Box-folder 19/10)
  - Vanity Fair, The MGM Girls and snapshots, April 1998 (Box-folder 21/1)
- Scrapbooks (Box 28-38)
  Clippings, correspondence, programs, photographs.
  - Bye Bye Birdie, Clippings, correspondence and programs (Box 32)
  - Champion, Gower and Marge, early career, Clippings and programs (Box 30)
  - Champion, Gower and Marge, early career, Clippings, programs and images (Box 34)
  - Champion, Gower and Marge, Photographs (Box 33)
  - Champion, Marge, early career, Clippings, drawings, photographs and programs (Box 33)
  - Champion, Marge: five decades of clippings and programs (Box 28)
  - Hello Dolly!, Clippings, programs, correspondence and images (Box 28)
  - Hello Dolly!, Clippings and images (Box 29)
  - Hello Dolly!, Clippings, images, photographs and programs (Box 30)
  - Hello Dolly!, Clippings, images and programs (Box 31)
  - Hello Dolly!, Correspondence, programs and clippings (Box 34)
  - I Do!, I Do!, Clippings, photographs and programs (Box 29)
  - Scrapbook, 1949-1953, Clippings, images, photographs and correspondence (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook, 1953-1955, Clippings, images, photographs and correspondence (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook, 1955-1960, Clippings, images, photographs and correspondence (Box 38)
  - 3 for Tonight, Clippings, programs and correspondence (Box 31)
  - Unbound scrapbooks with pages of clippings (Box-folder 35/6)
- Posters (Box 33, 35, Mapcase 4)
  - Berkshire Theater Festival, 60th Anniversary (Box-folder 35/1)
  - Everything I Have is Yours, Mini-poster (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Everything I Have is Yours (Mapcase-drawer 4/8)
  - 5-6-7-8... Dance (Box-folder 35/4)
  - Follies posters (Terrace Theater, Paper Mill Playhouse, Belasco Theater, Shaftesbury Theatre, Boston Colonial Theatre, copy) (Box-folder 35/3)
  - Give a Girl a Break, Mini-poster (Box-folder 33/3)
  - Jupiter’s Darling, Three posters (Mapcase-drawer 4/8)
  - Let’s Dance with Marge and Gower Champion book and Three for the Show on the bottom of the poster (Box-folder 35/5)
  - Lovely to Look At, Three mini-posters (Box-folder 33/1)
  - “Night of 100 Stars 2” (Mapcase-drawer 4/8)
  - Showboat (Mapcase-drawer 4/8)
  - Three for the Show, 1955 (Mapcase-drawer 4/8)
  - 3 for Tonight (Box-folder 35/2)
- Ephemera and Awards (Box 25, 32, 39)
  - Ernest Belcher’s shoes (Box 32)
  - Megaphone, 1925 (Box 39)
  - Awards:, Stepping Out exhibit case, 1988 Key to the city of Savannah, Georgia Bay Path College Doctor of Humane Letters, 2004 Bicentennial Salute from the City of Los Angeles, 1981 Commonwealth of Massachusetts Award, 1997 North Adams State College Doctor of Fine Arts, 1997 Documents of Dance Award from the Dance Library of Israel, 1985 Documents of Dance Award from the Dance Library of Israel to Gower Champion, 1992 (Box-folder 25/12)